<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Introduction on a Coding Monkey</title>
    <link>https://abl3t0nnile.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Introduction on a Coding Monkey</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><atom:link href="https://abl3t0nnile.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Host a GitHub Page with Hugo</title>
      <link>https://abl3t0nnile.github.io/docs/tutorials/setup_website/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://abl3t0nnile.github.io/docs/tutorials/setup_website/</guid>
      <description>Host a GitHub Page with Hugo #  This is a brief tutorial on how to set up a GitHub page with Hugo as a static content generator. It&amp;rsquo;s a simple and easy solution to maintain a personal website and blog. Especially if your a coder and used to working with git and the command line.
Prerequisites
The following topics are mandatory and won&amp;rsquo;t be covered in this tutorial:
 A working installation of Hugo Basic git knowledge A GitHub account Markdown syntax   1 Hugo #  Hugo is one of the key components for this project.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Markdown Syntax Guide</title>
      <link>https://abl3t0nnile.github.io/docs/library/markdown/syntax_guide/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://abl3t0nnile.github.io/docs/library/markdown/syntax_guide/</guid>
      <description>Markdown Syntax Guide #    This article offers a sample of basic Markdown syntax that can be used in Hugo content files.
This article is a shortened adaption of the great Grav original page.
For further details on the extended Markdown syntax of Hugo and Books - Theme see the corresponding articles.
 Let&amp;rsquo;s face it: Writing content for the Web is tiresome. WYSIWYG editors help alleviate this task, but they generally result in horrible code, or worse yet, ugly web pages.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Automate GitHub Hosting with Shell Scripts</title>
      <link>https://abl3t0nnile.github.io/docs/tutorials/shell_auto_blog/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://abl3t0nnile.github.io/docs/tutorials/shell_auto_blog/</guid>
      <description>Introduction #  This article will show how to simplify a lot of typing in the command line, when maintaining a GitHub page. It explores basic shell scripting, to automate post creation, staging and commit repository changes and pushing the updated site to the production repo of the project.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hugo Markdown Shortcodes</title>
      <link>https://abl3t0nnile.github.io/docs/library/markdown/hugo_shortcodes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://abl3t0nnile.github.io/docs/library/markdown/hugo_shortcodes/</guid>
      <description>Hugo Shortcodes #  This is a quick roundup on hugo shortcodes. These are snippets you can drop into your markdown, to further style a page. This article only covers the ones I find usefull. For additional instructions read the official Documentation.
1 Figure #  figure is an extension of the basic Markdown figure implementation. It provides a lot more options then the basic Markdown one.
The following syntax is used to place a figure inside a document:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Books - Theme Shortcodes</title>
      <link>https://abl3t0nnile.github.io/docs/library/markdown/books_shortcodes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://abl3t0nnile.github.io/docs/library/markdown/books_shortcodes/</guid>
      <description>Books - Theme Shortcodes #  This article gives a brief overview about special shortcodes, implemented by the Books - Theme for Hugo. The examples in this article are taken from the projects website. Since I don&amp;rsquo;t need all of the available options, I will only list those, being used on this page.
1 Columns #  Columns are the perfect tool for additional page styling. They provide a handy method to combine pictures and text.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Swift language Primer</title>
      <link>https://abl3t0nnile.github.io/docs/library/swift/primer/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://abl3t0nnile.github.io/docs/library/swift/primer/</guid>
      <description>A Swift Language Primer #  This document serves as a basic overview of the most important features and paradigms behind the Swift programming language. It provides some explanation about how each part of the language works and what syntax to use.
Variables and constants #  Swift differentiates two different types of variables using two different keywords when defining them. A variable or constant can be defined without initialising it, but if it is expected, that the variable will contain no value anytime during runtime, it has to be declared an optional using a special ?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hello Blog</title>
      <link>https://abl3t0nnile.github.io/posts/hello_blog/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Mar 2021 17:43:30 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://abl3t0nnile.github.io/posts/hello_blog/</guid>
      <description>Learning new things is fun! It&amp;rsquo;s energizing and if I really get into something I can&amp;rsquo;t let go of it. I get in over my head. I tend to choose a try-first-look-up-later style of learning. I love to tinker around and if I encounter a problem, I browse the web to find a solution. This often leads to chaos and surely minimizes my learning goals. Now and then I thought about starting a blog to keep track of my ideas and learnings, organize my efforts and saving me from re-learning a lot of things again and agin, because I didn&amp;rsquo;t took my time.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
